# Joonas Suuronen

### Engineer, Programmer, Game Developer

I am 24-year-old fresh Information and Communication technology graduate (IT engineer). I always have had a huge passion for technology and science. Especially computers and programming have always fascinated me. I watch science, technology and programming related videos and streams daily. Also, I always have some sort of programming projects active (usually related to video games) that I love to work on. Most people know me as an honest, active and social individual. I tend to do everything immediately and never let tasks pile up.







+358 400368833



Espoo, Suomi



github.com/Joonas98/GameScripts1

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Software Developer Metropolia, SAM-project

01/2022 - Present

Began by making thesis on this subject, but I was hired to continue further. To simplify, the project is about creating an application for simulation of surveillance of autonomus vehicles.

#### Details

- UI / UX Development.
- Team management.
- Other various tasks.

Contact: Pekko Lindblom, project manager pekko.lindblom@metropolia.fi, +358 504733152

### Game Developer

### Tutanet Ov

05/2020 - Present

Small group of developers have worked on game called "News Reacts" for years. I was hired to develop the UI and some core mechanics. The game shipped to Steam in 5/2022.

#### Details

- UI / UX.
- Core Mechanics.
- Optimization.

Contact: Jukka Soinila, CEO jukka.soinila@gmail.com, +358 415015856

### **Security Guard** Avarn Security

05/2017 - Present

#### Details

- Security services in many forms.
- Starting from 2022, mostly includes driving Nokia 5G vans.

## **EDUCATION**

Information and Communication Technology Metropolia Unviversity of Applied Sciences

08/2018 - 11/2022

## Security guard's degree

Edupoli and Amiedu

02/2018 - 02/2018

## Matriculation examination

Leppävaara Upper Secondary School

08/2014 - 06/2017

### **SKILLS**

Communication

Game Engines

UI / UX

Image & Audio handling

## **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

Various game projects (02/2019 - Present)

- Numerous game projects, mostly developed with Unity and C#.
- More serious project started late 2021 (WIP).

#### Chess AI (2019)

- Basic console chess with C++.
- Minimax algorithm with Alpha-Beta pruning.

#### ML / AI Game Director (2021)

- Machine learning artificial intelligence to direct events in a game.
- Made for client called Bigger Scope.
- Clusterizes playstyles and adapts to be more fun for each player.

### Company: Banaani Games (01/2023 - Present)

- Mostly for selling my own game projects
- Can also sell various software services through the company

## **LANGUAGES**

**Finnish** 

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Swedish

Limited Working Proficiency

German

Limited Working Proficiency

## INTERESTS

Technology

Programming

Video Games

Science

Gym

Mathematics

**Physics**